どうもー！みなさん、おひさしぶり！惣流・アスカ・ラングレーです！
大家好！好久不见！我是惣流·明日香·兰格雷！
Hello everyone! Long time no see! I'm Asuka Langley Soryu!
皆さんおなじみ、式波・アスカ・ラングレーです！
我是大家熟悉的式波·明日香·兰格雷！
And I'm the one you all know, Asuka Shikinami Langley!
二人合わせて、ダブルアスカ・ラングレーです！
我们俩合在一起，就是双重明日香·兰格雷！
Together, we are Double Asuka Langley!
こうして二人で会うのは初めてやね。お互い初めましてやからね。
像这样两人碰面还是第一次呢。毕竟彼此都是初次见面嘛。
This is the first time we've met like this. Nice to meet you.
いやさすがに29年ぶりの惣流版は緊張するわ。
哎呀，毕竟是时隔29年的惣流版，还真是紧张啊。
Man, being the Soryu version after 29 years is nerve-wracking.
まあ、お互い違う世界線やから。
嘛，毕竟我们身处不同的世界线。
Well, we are from different worldlines.
30周年とかのイベントでもないと、私らが出会うなんてまずないわな。
要不是30周年这种活动，我们俩根本不可能碰面。
If it weren't for a 30th-anniversary event, there's no way we'd ever meet.
しかしなんやね、式波さんも大変やったね。
不过话说回来，式波小姐你也挺辛苦的呢。
But anyway, you've had it rough too, Shikinami.
ドハレンチな格好でうろつき回ったり、
穿着超级不知廉耻的衣服到处晃悠，
Wandering around in super shameless outfits,
大人の格好で穴あきプラグスーツ着て寝そべったり。
或是以大人的模样穿着破洞驾驶服躺平。
or lying around in a torn plugsuit as an adult.
挙句、昔の感情をこくったり。
结果最后还把以前的感情给告白了。
And topping it off by confessing your old feelings.
私やったら恥ずかしくて穴掘って引きこもるわ。
换做是我，绝对羞得挖个洞躲起来了。
I'd die of embarrassment and hide in a hole.
それを言うなら惣流さんも、はだけた胸とパンツルックを
要这么说的话，惣流小姐你也是，敞开的胸口和内裤
If you want to talk about that, you had it rough too, Soryu,
シンジにガン見されたり、大変やったね。
被真嗣死盯着看，也挺惨的。
having Shinji stare at your exposed chest and panties.
その後の展開も含めたら、
再加上之后的展开，
Including what happened after,
私なんか恥ずかしくて裸でマイナス宇宙まで逃げ出すレベルやわ。
换做是我都要羞得光着身子逃到负宇宙去了。
I'd run naked straight to the Minus Universe.
まああんたも、使徒に食われかけたり、第13号機に取り込まれたりと…
嘛，你也是，差点被使徒吃掉，又被第13号机吞噬……
Well, you almost got eaten by an Angel, and absorbed by Unit-13...
しんどい目に遭ってますしな。
经历了不少倒霉事呢。
You've been through a lot of painful stuff.
いや負けずにあんたも、精神汚染に精神崩壊、
不不，你也不服输啊，精神污染加上精神崩溃，
No, you're not one to lose either—mind rape, mental breakdown,
おまけにエヴァシリーズに2号機ごと食われたり、えらい目に遭うとりましたがな。
最后连同二号机一起被量产机吃掉，也是遭了大罪啊。
and to top it off, getting eaten alive along with Unit-02 by the Eva Series. You went through hell.
ふもね。思い起こせば私らいっつもそういう役ばっか。
真是没完没了。回想起来我们俩总是扮演这种角色。
This is pointless. Come to think of it, we always get those kinds of roles.
いい加減私が幸せなラストを迎えたい。
差不多也该让我迎来一个幸福的结局了吧。
I want to have a happy ending for once.
そうね、特にあんたはその権利ありそうね。
是啊，特别是你看起来很有这个权利呢。
Yeah, especially you, you seem to have the right to one.
そう！私は私を幸せにしたいの！それだけ！
没错！我想让我自己获得幸福！仅此而已！
Exactly! I want to make myself happy! That's all!
私の時のラストって、主役のバカシンジにはハッピーエンドかもしれないけど、私は違う。
我那时的结局，对主角笨蛋真嗣来说或许是Happy End，但我可不一样。
My ending might have been a happy ending for that idiot Shinji, but not for me.
あのバカの自分世界に付き合わされて、首絞められて気持ち悪かっただけ。
被强行卷进那个笨蛋的自我世界，被掐了脖子，最后只留下一句“真恶心”。
I was forced to tag along in that idiot's inner world, got strangled, and just felt "disgusted."
それのどこに私の幸せがあるのよ！
那里面到底哪里有我的幸福啊！
Where is my happiness in that?!
ようやく現れた世界線書き換えチャンス。
好不容易出现了改写世界线的机会。
Finally, a chance to rewrite the worldline.
たとえ尺は短くても、ついに手にした主役の話なのよ！
就算时长很短，这终于也是我当主角的故事了！
Even if the runtime is short, I finally have a story where I'm the protagonist!
バカシンジとくっつくにしても、他のシチュエーションがあるでしょう！もっとわかりやすく！
就算是和笨蛋真嗣凑一对，也该有其他的展开吧！更加简单易懂的！
Even if I end up with idiot Shinji, there have to be other situations! Something easier to understand!
エモーショナルに幸せそうな流れが！それが欲しいのよ！
那种充满情感、看起来就很幸福的剧情走向！我想要的是那个！
An emotional, happy-looking progression! That's what I want!
それが私の切ない、たった一つの小さな望み！
这就是我那悲切的、唯一的小小愿望！
That is my desperate, single little wish!
いいね。その願い、僕が叶えてあげよう。
不错呢。那个愿望，就让我来帮你实现吧。
Sounds good. I will grant that wish of yours.
あんたは引っ込んでて！
你给我退下！
You stay out of this!
シンジ一人まともに幸せにできないあんたの世話にはならないわよ！
我才不要连真嗣一个人都无法让他正常获得幸福的你来帮忙呢！
I'm not taking help from someone who can't even make Shinji normally happy!
どうせそれらしいこと遠回しに言うだけで、余計訳わかんないカオスにしちゃうだけでしょう！
反正你也只会拐弯抹角地说些似是而非的话，最后只会搞出更加让人摸不着头脑的混沌局面罢了！
You'll probably just say something cryptic and turn it into an even more confusing, chaotic mess!
なんかごめん。
总觉得抱歉啊。
Kind of sorry about that.
あの、アスカ…
那个，明日香……
Um, Asuka...
バカシンジは黙ってて！
笨蛋真嗣你给我闭嘴！
Idiot Shinji, keep quiet!
さてどうするの？
那么，要怎么做？
Now, what should we do?
私の世界にはあの少年以外に、もう一人ゲームチェンジャーがいるけど。
在我的世界里，除了那个少年，还有另一个人能改变局势。
In my world, besides that boy, there's one other game changer.
新人に頼りたくない。私の幸せは、私の力でもぎ取るの！
我不想依赖新人（玛丽）。我的幸福，要靠我自己的力量去夺取！
I don't want to rely on the newbie. I will seize my happiness with my own hands!
その意気やよしね。ならば碇シンジのパターンを試してみましょう。
这份气势不错呢。那么，就来试试碇真嗣的模式吧。
That's the spirit. Then let's try the pattern of Ikari Shinji.
何それ？とにかく寝る。
那是什么？总之就是睡觉。
What's that? Anyway, just sleep.
そして、ドアップで目を開く。すると何か違う展開になってる。
然后，给个大特写睁开眼睛。接着剧情就会发生改变。
And then, I open my eyes in a close-up. Then things take a different turn.
ああ、あれ。それをリピートしてれば、いつかはあなたが望む世界が来るわよ。
啊啊，那个啊。只要不断重复那个，总有一天会迎来你所期望的世界的。
Ah, that. If you keep repeating that, the world you desire will eventually come.
うん、それ、試してみる価値ありそうね。
嗯，这个，似乎有尝试的价值呢。
Yeah, that seems worth a try.
じゃ、寝るわよ。
那我睡了哦。
Well then, I'm going to sleep.
おやすみ、アスカ。
晚安，明日香。
Goodnight, Asuka.
エヴァンゲリオン初号機、リフトオフ！
Evangelion初号机，发射！
Evangelion Unit-01, lift off!
シンジくん、しっかりして！早く！早く起き上がるのよ！
真嗣君，振作一点！快点！快点站起来啊！
Shinji, pull yourself together! Hurry! Hurry up and get up!
本部属に、飛行物体、ユーロNERVの機体です！
报告总部，飞行物是欧洲NERV的机体！
To headquarters. The flying object belongs to Euro NERV!
まさか
难道说
No way!
やはりEVA2号機、完成していたの。
果然EVA二号机，已经完成了啊。
So EVA Unit-02 was completed after all.
真の勇者は、必ずピンチに間に合わせるものなのよ！
真正的勇者，必定会在危机时刻赶到的！
A true hero always makes it in time for a pinch!
うおりゃあー！おおお！
欧拉——！哦哦哦！
Uryaaah! Ohhh!
私が来てからにはもノープロブレム。貴方瞬殺よ！
既然我来了就根本没问题。秒杀你啊！
This is no problem since I have come! You're the one getting instantly killed!
うわああ！あれ？
哇啊啊！哎？
Uwaaah! Huh?
カット！あんたバカ！？私がこんなドジ踏むわけないでしょ！
Cut！你笨蛋吗！？我怎么可能犯这种低级错误！
Cut! Are you an idiot?! There's no way I'd make such a stupid mistake!
それにこの展開、あんたの話も混じってんじゃん！
而且这剧情，连你的故事也混进去了吧！
Besides, this development has your story mixed into it too!
リテイクよ、リテイク！
重拍，重拍！
Retake! Retake!
了解。じゃ、おやすみ、アスカ。
了解。那么，晚安，明日香。
Roger. Well then, goodnight, Asuka.
カット！何よこれ！私が巨大化してどうすんのよ！
Cut！这算什么啊！我巨大化了是要干嘛啦！
Cut! What is this?! What am I supposed to do being giant?!
力こそ全てかと思って。
我还以为力量就是一切呢。
I thought power was everything.
私の幸せはそうじゃない！リテイクよ！リテイク！
我的幸福才不是那样！重拍！重拍！
That's not what my happiness is! Retake! Retake!
了解。じゃ、おやすみ、アスカ。
了解。那么，晚安，明日香。
Roger. Well then, goodnight, Asuka.
心を静かに落ち着かせる。戦いに勝つために必要なことだ。
让心境平静下来。这是为了赢得战斗所必须的。
Calm your heart down. It's necessary in order to win.
31手先で君の詰みだ。
再过31步就是你的死局了。
Checkmate in 31 moves.
えぇーい！てい！たっ！カット！
诶——！嘿！哈！Cut！
Eii! Tei! Ta! Cut!
カット！何よこれ！なんで私が将棋指してんのよ！
Cut！这算什么啊！为什么我在下将棋啊！
Cut! What is this?! Why am I playing Shogi?!
勝負事が好きかと思って。
我还以为你喜欢分个胜负呢。
I thought you liked competitions.
ズルして勝っても意味ない！次よ、次！ラブなロマンスをちょうだい！
作弊赢了也没有意义啊！下一个，下一个！给我来点浪漫爱情！
There's no point in winning by cheating! Next! Next! Give me some sweet romance!
了解。じゃ、おやすみ、アスカ。
了解。那么，晚安，明日香。
Roger. Well then, goodnight, Asuka.
うわ！凄い景色！
哇！好美的景色！
Wow! Great sight!
ここは、第3新東京市のマチュピチュって言われているんだよ。
这里，被称为第三新东京市的马丘比丘哦。
This place is known as the Machu Picchu of Tokyo-3.
これから、もっといろんな世界をアスカと見たい。
今后，我还想和明日香一起去看更多不同的世界。
From now on, I want to see many more worlds with you, Asuka.
シンジ…いやだ、照れくさいじゃん！でも、嬉しい。
真嗣……讨厌啦，多难为情啊！不过，好开心。
Shinji... No, that's so embarrassing! But, I'm happy.
シンジ？
真嗣？
Shinji?
カット！ちょっと！シンジは大丈夫？
Cut！等一下！真嗣你没事吧？
Cut! Wait! Shinji, are you okay?
うん。
嗯。
Yeah.
続き…
继续
Continue
もう死ぬかと思うた
还以为要死了
Thought I would gonna die
ならいい
那就好
Well then
続きいく？
要继续吗？
Shall we continue?
も、いい。恥ずかしすぎる。次にして。
还是算了。太羞耻了。换下一个吧。
No, that's enough. It's too embarrassing. Next one.
じゃ、おやすみ、アスカ。
那么，晚安，明日香。
Well then, goodnight, Asuka.
カット！意味不明！リテイク！
Cut！意义不明！重拍！
Cut! This makes no sense! Retake!
この大空に、翼を広げ
在这广阔天空中，张开翅膀
Spread your wings in this vast sky
エッチ！
H！
H!
カット！あんたのところのファーストの真似じゃん！リテイク！
Cut！这根本就是在模仿你们那边的第一适格者（绫波丽）吧！重拍！
Cut! You're just copying the First Child (Rei) from your side! Retake!
カット！何よこれ！
Cut！这算什么啊！
Cut! What is this?!
私見たく一人は嫌かと思って。
我以为你像我一样不喜欢一个人呢。
I thought you hated being alone, like I do.
そうだけど、私はいらない！欲しいのは私じゃない人！
话是这么说，但我不需要另一个我啊！我想要的是除了我以外的人！
True, but I don't need another me! I want someone who isn't me!
そうね。おやすみ、アスカ。
也是呢。晚安，明日香。
Fair enough. Goodnight, Asuka.
カット！何よこれ、恥ずかしすぎ！
Cut！这算什么啊，太羞耻了吧！
Cut! What is this, it's too embarrassing!
あなたも早く大人になりたいかと思って。
我还以为你也想早点变成大人呢。
I thought you wanted to become an adult sooner too.
こんなことじゃない！いい加減幸せループを見つけてよ！
才不是指这种事！差不多给我找到幸福的循环吧！
Not like this! Hurry up and find a happy loop already!
分かった。おやすみ、アスカ。
知道了。晚安，明日香。
Understood. Goodnight, Asuka.
えらいわ、アスカちゃん。よく頑張ったわね。
真了不起啊，明日香。你很努力了呢。
You're so great, Asuka. You did so well.
アスカちゃんは天才ね。ママの誇り。本当にいい子ね。
明日香是天才呢。是妈妈的骄傲。真是个好孩子。
Asuka is a genius. Mommy's pride. You really are a good girl.
アスカちゃんの好きなことしていいのよ。
明日香做自己喜欢的事情就好了哦。
You can do whatever you like, Asuka.
ママはいつでも、アスカちゃんのことを見てますからね。
妈妈无论什么时候，都会看着明日香的。
Mommy is always watching over you.
カット！ダメ、しっくりこない。居心地悪い。
Cut！不行，感觉不对劲。太不自在了。
Cut! No, it doesn't feel right. It's uncomfortable.
こんなの私が私じゃない感じ。これは絶対ない。
这样总觉得我都不像我了。这个绝对不行。
This feels like I'm not even me. This is an absolute no.
そう…そうね。おやすみ、アスカ。
是吗……也是呢。晚安，明日香。
I see... Right. Goodnight, Asuka.
間も無く、列車がまいります
列车马上就要进站了
The train is arriving shortly.
危ないですから、黄色い線の内側までお下がりください。
注意危险。请退到黄色线内侧。
For your safety, please stand back behind the yellow line.
誰だ？
是谁？
Who's there?
バスト87のいい女。
三围Bust 87的好女人。
A hot woman with an 87 bust.
ごめーと
抱歉啦~。
Sorry~!
カット！悪くない流れだけど、
Cut！虽然走向不算坏，
Cut! The flow wasn't bad,
私は私のいた世界で幸せになりたい。
但我想在属于我的世界里获得幸福。
but I want to be happy in the world I was in.
エヴァのない世界で？
在没有EVA的世界里？
In a world without Eva?
まもなく、2番線に第2星ヶ谷大倉行き特急リニアがまいります。
开往第2星谷大仓的特急磁悬浮列车即将驶入2号站台。
The Limited Express Linear bound for 2nd Star Valley Great Warehouse will shortly arrive at Track 2.
危ないですから、黄色い線の内側までお下がりください。
注意危险。请退到黄色安全线内侧
For your safety, please stand back behind the yellow line.
2番線の電車は、14時20分発、第2星ヶ谷大倉行きの政府専用特別列車です。
2号站台的列车，是14点20分发车，开往第2星谷大仓的政府专用特别列车。
The train at Track 2 is the 14:20 Government Exclusive Special Train bound for 2nd Star Valley Great Warehouse.
許可のない方のご乗車は固く禁じられておりますので、ご注意ください。
严禁未经许可的人员乘车，请多加留意。
Boarding by unauthorized personnel is strictly prohibited. Please be advised.
繰り返します。2番線の電車は、14時20分発、第2星ヶ谷大倉行きの政府専用特別列車です。
重复。2号站台的列车，是14点20分发车，开往第2星谷大仓的政府专用特别列车。
Repeat. The train at Track 2 is the 14:20 Government Exclusive Special Train bound for 2nd Star Valley Great Warehouse.
許可のない方のご乗車は固く禁じられておりますので、ご注意ください。
严禁未经许可的人员乘车，请多加留意。
Boarding by unauthorized personnel is strictly prohibited. Please be advised.
アスカ。一緒に行こう。
明日香。一起走吧。
Asuka. Let's go together.
ありがとう、シンジ。でももういい。
谢谢你，真嗣。但是已经够了。
Thank you, Shinji. But it's okay now.
この穏やかな優しい世界は、私のいるところじゃない。
这个平静温柔的世界，并不是我该待的地方。
This peaceful, gentle world is not where I belong.
私が守るべきところだった。それに、もう夢に頼るのはやめる。
而是我曾经应该去守护的地方。而且，我不再依靠梦境了。
It was the place I was supposed to protect. Besides, I'm done relying on dreams.
現実の自分の力で幸せになる。
我要靠现实中自己的力量去获得幸福。
I will become happy with my own strength in reality.
それが一番私らしいやり方だって、分かった。
我已经明白了，那才是最符合我风格的做法。
I realized that's the way that suits me best.
どう？懐かしいでしょ？
怎么样？很怀念吧？
How is it? Nostalgic, right?
まあ、悪くないわね。
嘛，还不赖嘛。
Well, it's not bad.
みんな練習したのよ。
大家都有好好练习过哦。
Everyone practiced.
なんかエモいわね。
总觉得有点感伤呢。
It feels kinda emotional.
人前で歌ったことないから、照れるな。
因为没在别人面前唱过歌，还挺害羞的。
I've never sung in front of people before, so it's a bit embarrassing.
お前が何回！
你干啥！
What are you doing!
もうあんたにも頼らない！私は私！
我也不会再依赖你了！我就是我！
I won't rely on you anymore either! I am me!
人がいる限り、私はエヴァに乗り続ける！
只要人类还在，我就会继续驾驶EVA！
As long as there are people, I will keep piloting the Eva!
私の幸せは、みんなを守ったその先の未来にある！きっとな！
我的幸福，就在守护了大家之后的未来里！一定是这样！
My happiness lies in the future after I've protected everyone! I'm sure of it!
だって、私はエヴァンゲリオン2号機パイロット、
因为，我可是Evangelion二号机的驾驶员，
Because I am the pilot of Evangelion Unit-02,
惣流・アスカ・ラングレーだから！
惣流·明日香·兰格雷！
Asuka Langley Soryu!